By far the most terrifying film you will ever see.
An Inconvenient Truth is a documentary film directed by Davis Guggenheim.
A documentary on Al Gore's campaign to make the issue of
global warming a recognized problem worldwide.
Self, played by Al Gore.
Various (voice), played by Billy West.
Self (archive footage), played by Ronald Reagan.
Self (archive footage), played by George W. Bush.
Self (archive footage), played by George H. W. Bush.
An Inconvenient Truth is a 2006 American documentary film directed by Davis Guggenheim about former vice
president of the United States Al Gore's campaign to educate people about global warming.
The film features a slide show that, by Gore's own estimate, he has
presented over 1,000 times to audiences worldwide.
The idea to document Gore's efforts came from producer Laurie David, who saw his presentation at a town
hall meeting on global warming, which coincided with the opening of The Day After Tomorrow.
Laurie David was so inspired by his slide show that she, with producer Lawrence Bender, met with
Guggenheim, and Co-Producer Lesley Chilcott, to adapt the presentation into a film.
Premiering at the 2006 Sundance Film Festival and opening in New York City and Los Angeles on May 24, 2006, the film was a
critical and commercial success, winning two Academy Awards for Best Documentary Feature and Best Original Song.
The film grossed $24 million in the US and $26 million in other countries' box offices,
becoming the eleventh highest grossing documentary film to date in the United States.
Since the film's release, An Inconvenient Truth has been credited for raising international
public awareness of global warming and reenergizing the environmental movement.
The documentary has also been included in science curricula in schools around the
world, which has spurred some controversy due to some of the data it used.
A sequel to the film, titled An Inconvenient Sequel: Truth
to Power, was released on July 28, 2017.
The film explores themes of politics,
self-destruction, truth, climate, climate change.